What? It's his birthday today?!
Yes.
That's great to hear!
Imagine giving him a birthday gift when
you're alone together enjoying the night view!
The night view?
Yup!
But...
I haven't the slightest clue what to give him.
What does he like?
What he likes...
Um...
Katsuda Side Dish Store's tonkatsu?
Hm... That might not have quite
the right impact as a gift.
What else...
Dolls?
Kiyobashi Camera Multimedia, Kikyoji Store
Oh, when you mentioned dolls,
you meant figures.
Toys & Figures
He has these "hero" figures on his shelf.
Oh, okay... So what kinds
of heroes does he like?
Well...
Capsule Toy Section
Oh, I believe...
Succulent
Happy Murderous
Instinct Friends
Dancing Haniwa
I saw that one in Master Hitoyoshi's room!
This is a capsule toy!
You can get a random toy
in the picture for 300 yen a try.
So in order to get this black one...
Happy Murderous
Instinct Friends
You have to keep trying until
the one you want comes out.
Are you going to try it?
Yes!
Capsule Toy Section
Exchange
Another Crystal...
It's all over.
No matter what I do, I...
Oh! Ms. Yuki, your nose...
Your nose!
I'm not even worthy of giving
Master Hitoyoshi a present.
Episode 12: The Joyous Tidings You All Bring.
Um, Miss...
Shall I teach you a spell you can chant
when something you want eludes you?
A spell?
That's right.
Firstly...
Banish those tears!
These machines are embodiments
of evil that prey on the weak!
You can't just rely on the gods to save you!
Huh?
If you want it, seize it with your own hands!
The desire sensor is a hoax!
Steel your heart...
and pull the handle with killing intent!
Wha?
S-Steel my heart with killing intent...
"Come home, or die!"
When you pull, you must make that your mantra!
Yes, sir! I'll give it a try!
You're really trying it?!
Come home...
or die.
H-Her killing intent is overwhelming!
Gulp...
H-He came home!
G-Glad it worked out.
I-I can't thank you enough!
No worries. I was thinking about how
I used to tell my son the same thing.
So I couldn't just sit back and watch.
I'm glad I was able to help.
Well, I'd better get back to my shopping.
He was as kind as he was handsome.
He did seem most considerate.
Big Brother...
Ack?!
Chop!
It's already snack time!
Just how long are you gonna sleep?
Huh? What happened
to the New Year's shrine visit?
Never mind that!
Dad's gonna be here any second!
What? Seriously?!
I've gone to the shrine.
-Yuki
The shrine...
Wait, Ms. Yuki's not here?
Huh?
This is bad!
I haven't explained anything about Dad to her!
You haven't?!
N-No...
Why?!
You guys live together!
You could have told her any time!
Well, just because someone's close by
doesn't mean you can just
talk to them about anything.
Huh?
That's right. Even with my actual family...
I wasn't able to ask Mom why
she was leaving all of a sudden,
and I couldn't ask Dad why he
looked the way he did about it,
let alone tell him that this was the
first time I actually felt afraid of him.
After that, Dad got transferred
overseas for work,
and he rarely came home after that,
leaving a babysitter in charge of me instead.
I still can't bring myself to ask
why I'm living separately from Mom.
The anger I saw in his eyes that day...
I'm terrified of finding out
it was because of me.
That's why I'm honestly afraid
of how he'll react to Ms. Yuki.
Big Brother...
You have a new message from Naka Hikage.
Hikage...
I had lots of fun at the shrine today!
Just now, Ms. Yuki and I parted ways, but...
She seemed sad from the fortune she received,
so please try and cheer her up.
Cheer... her up...
I've returned home.
Oh, Ms. Yuki, welcome—
Your eyes?!
I had fun visiting the shrine.
Your eyes are swollen as heck!
Did something happen?!
Oh, no...
Nothing... really.
I'll go get changed right away.
Ms. Yuki!
Yes?
Um, my dad will be here soon, but...
I haven't told him that
you're a former assassin,
or that you wear a maid outfit,
or anything like that, so...
Actually, it's fine.
Go ahead and get changed.
All right.
What the heck am I panicking about?
Trying to hide Ms. Yuki,
who's doing her best to be normal,
would be like saying that
I don't think she's normal at all.
Are you sure about this?
Yeah, I am.
No matter what Dad says,
it's my turn to protect Ms. Yuki!
You've grown so much!
Oh, but what you said just now...
You gotta say that stuff to Ms. Yuki!
It's a big, fat waste just saying it to me!
You idiot! One more time! From the top!
And I'll get the whole thing on camera!
Come on! Quit teasing me!
Starting the new year off with a bang, huh?
Da—
I see you two are getting along
as well as ever.
Dad!
Welcome home...
Good to be back.
Welcome home!
Riko! Have you been behaving yourself?
I have!
Aw, but why'd you have to go and grow a beard?
The simple, clean-shaven look
is way more popular with the ladies!
Well, the only lady I need
to be popular with is you, Riko.
That's my dad. 100,000 points!
Um, Dad...
It's about the maid I mentioned before.
Yeah, the new housekeeper, right?
The house really is remarkably clean.
I'll have to thank her personally.
She's not a housekeeper, exactly...
She's a bona fide maid.
And this maid, Ms. Yuki, has some
history from her previous job.
There's a whole lot I need to explain to you.
A maid... named Ms. Yuki?
Master Hitoyoshi.
"Yuki." A maid's dress.
An assassin by trade.
You're the man from before...
I see.
So you are Ms. Xue.
Thank you so much for earlier.
It was nothing. Don't worry about it.
No, you were a great help.
Yeah?
Well, glad to hear it.
It seemed very important to you.
Huh? What's going on?
You guys know each other?
To think you were Master Hitoyoshi's father...
My apologies, Master Hitoyoshi.
I should be handling the refreshments...
It's okay.
Thanks!
Thank you.
So, when did you first
start working for Mr. Hamuro?
Right. It was about three years ago
that he became my master.
He told me of a maid who was also an assassin,
but I didn't think you'd be this beautiful.
Right, right?
She's perfect from any angle!
Right, Mochita?
But... Now I see.
It's been half a year since
Mr. Hamuro's passing, huh?
He was a brilliant and admirable man.
Yes. It is a great loss.
This whole time, I was thinking how
I'd explain Ms. Yuki to my dad, but...
You see, I met him when
I was working in London.
There's a part of Dad I don't know.
And the last time we met,
about two years ago, he asked me...
There's a part of Ms. Yuki I don't know.
"If I die, there's a girl I'd like you
to take in for me."
It's almost like I'm listening to a
conversation between two strangers.
"Would you treat her as one of your own?"
I see...
Arrangements being made behind my back...
The feeling that I'm being left behind
all on my own again...
The sting of loneliness.
But you knew she was an assassin
all along, right?
I'm surprised you said yes to that!
Well, at the time, Mr. Hamuro
was still alive and well,
and I didn't really think he was serious.
And besides...
You two inherited your mother's vampire blood,
so I figured, what's one
little assassin gonna do?
Ohmigosh! Who knew these charming fangs
held a deeper secret?!
Vampire...
Oh, come to think of it,
when I dressed up as a vampire
last Halloween...
I thought I felt my blood respond!
Riko, you're so cute.
Dad's always been this way, hasn't he?
Whenever there's something
he wants to hide or avoid facing,
What is it, boy? You want a pat, too, Mochita?
he brushes it off with a joke
or remains silent.
Who's a squishy ol' mochi cake?
So I gradually stopped prying,
I'm happy for you, Mochita!
Squishy squish!
and began to pick up on his cues... Oh.
I get it. I...
I had lots of fun at the shrine today!
Just now, Ms. Yuki and I parted ways, but...
She seemed sad from the fortune she received,
so please try and cheer her up.
You gotta say that stuff to Ms. Yuki!
Back then and even now... I've always kept
things to myself so as not to burden others.
My dad, Ms. Yuki... I don't tell them anything.
And instead of trying to learn about them,
I just wait for them to tell me.
Now then, Riko.
It's time I took you home.
What? Already?
I have things I need to speak
with your mother about.
It's Big Brother's birthday, you know?!
Hitoyoshi doesn't like it being celebrated.
Hitoyoshi.
Happy sixteenth birthday.
This is from your mother and I.
Thank you.
Sorry to say this after you went through
the trouble of cleaning the house,
but I have a work meeting I need to attend,
so I'll be staying at a hotel.
Squishy, squishy!
Right.
See ya!
Everything I wanted to say to him...
Am I just going to leave it all unsaid again?
Private
Well then, see ya!
Yokoya
Am I really going to let him go
without saying anything?
No.
This time, I need to...
Dad!
Ms. Yuki...
Ms. Yuki can stay here, right?
What do you want?
I-I...
I want her to stay!
I see.
Well, you're sixteen now. Do as you like.
I'll gently break the news to your mother.
Okay.
Yokoya
For the first time...
Just once, I was able to tell him
what was on my mind.
Was I able to protect Ms. Yuki?
Yokoya
Um...
Incoming Call
Dad
Dad?
Hello?
Sorry, Hitoyoshi.
Would you mind putting on Ms. Yuki?
Ms. Yuki.
Yes?
Dad wants to speak to you.
Yes, this is Yuki.
Ms. Yuki.
Yes?
Sorry to put you through all this.
I wasn't able to ask in front of him, but...
Is there anything unsatisfactory
about your situation?
I'm quite all right. Everything is fine.
Master Hitoyoshi is taking
very good care of me.
I see.
Ms. Yuki.
He's changed.
Or rather, he's trying to change.
And I think that's because...
you're by his side.
Thank you.
Please take good care of Hitoyoshi.
I will.
Ms. Yuki?
Master Hitoyoshi.
Would you like to go see
the night view with me?!
Huh, the night view...
Sure, I guess?
Just where are we—
If you'll excuse me.
Huh? Wha?!
Yokoya
M-Ms. Yuki?!
What's all this, all of a sudden?
U-Um...
It's... not quite... night yet... but...
there's a lovely... view of the town... so...
You're so out of breath that
you're clutching your chest?!
Are you all right?!
M-Master Hitoyoshi...
Happy birthday.
Don't tell me the reason she was clutching
her chest and being all fidgety was...
I just... had to give this to you today...
I see.
And here I was, getting it all wrong.
Just as I thought.
If you always bottle everything up inside,
no one else will understand how you feel.
What I want to tell Ms. Yuki is...
my hopes for our future together.
This is from an anime that got kinda popular
ten years ago. I was massively into it.
I was always whining selfishly to my dad
to get me merchandise from it.
Master Hitoyoshi... being selfish?
I, uh...
Up you go!
When I was little, I used to look up to my dad.
It was like he knew everything
and could do anything.
To me, my dad was the first hero I ever knew.
But ever since the day my mom left,
it was like I didn't know
anything about my dad anymore.
It really sucks to look up to someone, only to
have it all come crashing down, you know?
Even now, I'm afraid of him.
I'd worry, like... What if I was honest
with him and he just shut me down?
I didn't want to be hurt any more
than I already was, so...
I spent ten years avoiding him,
and then I realized
that I didn't know how we
could be a family anymore.
But I...
I don't want that to happen with you, Ms. Yuki.
If you came here to find a family of your own,
then that's what I want to be for you—
someone you can talk to about
the happy times, the sad times,
anything and everything in-between—as family.
Would you be part of my family?
And I know I'm being kinda formal
about this out of nowhere.
Like, as far as everyone else is concerned,
we're already cousins,
so it's like, why even ask, but...
Ms. Yuki?!
D-Did I say something I shouldn't have?!
No. My apologies.
How peculiar.
It seems that tears still flow...
even in times of happiness.
I would love to be part of your family.
Is that really possible?
For someone like me?
A-Absolutely! In fact, it has
to be you, and only you!
Because...
I love you, Ms. Yuki!
Of course! I love you, too, Master Hitoyoshi!
Oh.
So this is how my New Year's turmoil ends.
It's better this way.
If that's what it takes to preserve
Ms. Yuki's innocent, childlike smile.
I already knew that Ms. Yuki's "love"
is more like "endearment," but...
I think this is the first time
I've experienced real heartbreak.
I love you, Ms. Yuki!